# MOHD BAKHTIAR AB HALIM PROJECT ENGINEER

Mobile number +60199344752

Email address masstre\_82@yahoo.com.sg

Address D-4-17 Tiara Duta Condo, Tmn Putra Sulaiman

68000 Ampang Selangor

**Born:** 18<sup>th</sup> July 1982

Nationality: Malaysian

Marrial Status: Married

## **QUALIFICATIONS**

B. Eng in M Chemical-Gas Engineering, (Faculty of Chemical & Natural Resources Engineering) from University Technology of Malaysia (UTM), Skudai, Johor, 2006

## **PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATION**

- Registered Engineer with Board of Engineer Malaysia (BEM No. 53843 A)
- Member of The Institution of Engineers, Malaysia (IEM No: G 38907)

### **PROFESSIONAL COURSES**

- Attended NDT Magnetic Particle Inspection course by TWI, UK, June 2010
- Attended Construction Site Management Planning by ABM, Jan 2010
- Attended NDT Radiographic Interpretation course by TWI, UK, Sept 2009
- Attended AVEVA 3D Simulation training by AVEVA, Dec 2008
- Attended Storage Tanks course by CMT, Apr 2008
- Attended AutoCAD Level 1 course by UTM, Nov 2005

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

RNZ INTEGRATED (M) SDN BHD (Sep 2011 - present) Menara Great Eastern, Kuala Lumpur

Position: Project Engineer

#### PROJECT INVOLVED:

- Baronia Rejuvenation Workscoping and Engineering for PCSB
- Provision of Process Safety Studies for Carigali Hess Operating Company Sdn Bhd
- Laser Scanning and As Builting Exercise for Cakerawala Production platform (CKP) and Riser platform (CKR)
- Provision for Front End Engineering Design (FEED) for SKO Pipeline Rehabilitation Project
- Provision of Umbrella Contract for Engineering and Technical Support Services for Carigali Hess Operating Company Sdn Bhd
- West Desaru Engineering Support for Provision of Hook-Up and Commissioning Services for Shapadu Energy & Engineering Services / Petrofac Malaysia Limited
- Provision of Engineering Consultancy Services for Petronas Carigali (Turkmenistan) Sdn Bhd
- Provision of Engineering and Technical Support Services (ETSS) for Carigali Hess Operating Company Sdn Bhd



## **EXPERIENCE SUMMARY**

Since graduation in 2006, Bakhtiar has been working for eight (10) years in Oil & Gas and Construction Industries

He had worked for Juru Rubcoil Sdn Bhd for four (4) months as Project / Sales Engineer, Dynamic Quorum Sdn Bhd for two (2) years as Process Engineer and KIC Oil & Gas Sdn Bhd for three (3) years as Project Engineer.

He has been working with RNZ since September 2011 as one of the Project Engineer.

He has experience in the oil and gas industry covering preparation of project planning and execution, engineering development, onshore fabrication and commissioning, liaison with internal and external Clients and supervising contractors, vendors and fabricators.

Familiar with a range of proprietary software including PDMS, Ms Words, Ms Excel, AutoCAD and Math Lab and familiar with relevant international codes and standards including API, ASME, ANSI, TEMA, NFPA, and PTS.

#### RESPONSIBILITY:

- Conduct internal and external meetings / interface interdisciplinary issues / scope of work clarification with the Client
- Develop project schedule, cost control, inter discipline check, manhour and resources estimation
- Prepare and coordinate project progress reporting
- Monitor and follow up deliverables submission and ensure the weighted of project progress are always in acceptable boundary limit
- Initiate, recommend and effect improvements in the project plan in pro-active manner such that quality, costs and time scales are met
- Plan and coordinate the arrangement for site visit / offshore works

Plan and coordinate technical review / PDMS review meeting involving all disciplines

- Coordinate 3rd Party studies including safety audits, noise and vibration studies, HAZOP, etc
- Prepare, plan and coordinate the invoicing, project invoice plan and follow up payment with the Client

## KIC OIL & GAS SDN BHD (Feb 2008 - Aug 2011) **Kuala Lumpur**

Position: Project Engineer

Work Scope:

EPCC Project to develop a Petroleum Hub and Bunkering Facilities on a reclaimed island off Tanjung Bin Johor worth RM1.3b for Asia Petroleum Hub Sdn. Bhd.

- Involved in preparing Project Execution Plan, assist Project Manager to establish Document Management Control Procedure.
- Assist Project Manager to review on Conceptual Design, Basic Engineering and Detailed Engineering according to Owner's Requirement and to specified codes and standards such as API, ASME, ASTM, and NFPA.
- Assist Project Manager to review PFD, P&ID, GA drawings, technical specifications and datasheets on the completeness of the design, identify any under design or over design, identify cost-cut items and check document discrepancies/consistency for key engineering documents.
- Involved in technical review meeting and discussion on process and mechanical piping.
- Involved in project's Hazard and Operability Study (HAZOP).
- Assist Project Manager to review vendor's technical evaluation, control and update local authority liaison register, prepare slide presentations/flowcharts to address management key issues to the client.
- Assist Project Planner/Scheduler to monitor/ update engineering progress on Project Schedule and to estimate Piping Construction Material
- Assist Procurement Team to prepare technical requirement in tendering document for pipes, flanges and fittings procurement.
- Assist Lead Engineer to review MTO and Pipe Stress Analysis on critical lines to ensure piping flexibility and equipment nozzle loads satisfies ASME B31.3 requirements.
- During construction stage, join Construction Management Team to monitor and co-ordinate the construction activities, materials, equipment's and machineries.
- Inspect and check that all construction works are in accordance with drawings and specifications while maintain and update the status of revise drawings and submittals with the designer.
- Liaise and resolve with the technical support team on design co-ordination issues, provide support to Resident
- Investigate and collect site information, review IOW's daily site diary, provide technical guidance to IOW.
- Compile and analyse data in project reports (daily/ weekly and monthly) for review by Project Manager.

  Monitor surveillance of welding, NDT, PMI and PWHT activities on subcontractors designated area of responsibility.
- Review Welding Procedure Specification produced by Welding Inspector and witnesses all field tests including hydrotest (HT), dye Penetrant (PT) and ultrasonic test (UT).

## DYNAMIC OUORUM SDN BHD (Nov 2006 - Jan 2008) **Kuala Lumpur**

Position: Process Engineer

Involved in the design of Bulk Fuel Installation (BFI) at Langkawi for 2 nos of 500m3 Automotive Diesel Oil (ADO) Storage Tank

Lead the Process team to develop the design basis, develop PFD and P&ID, mass and energy balance, piping optimization, produce process calculation, establish process datasheets, establish design for Fire Protection System, establish the Cause and Effect Diagram, lead process team in Process Safety Review etc

Seconded to QIpmc Sdn Bhd on Oil Terminal Project at Tanjung Bin Johor.

## JURU RUBCOIL SDN BHD (Jun 2006 - Oct 2006) Kuala Lumpur

Position: Project/Sales Engineer

## NATURE OF WORK DONE:

- Work as a sales engineer for design and construction of processing Plant, Equipment and Machineries such as heat exchangers, oil skimmers, driers, mixers, ovens etc.

  Involved in the design of industrial Oil Interceptor for oily water treatment

## PREFERENCES:

Willing to travel / relocate	Moderate
Current Salary	RM 6000
Expected Salary	RM 7000
Availability	Immediate